Finding Aid for Undergraduate Library (University of Michigan) records, 1957-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Undergraduate Library (University of Michigan) records 1957-1982
University of Michigan. Undergraduate Library.
2 linear feet and one outsize scrapbook.
861122 BImu Bimu C430 2
University of Michigan library devoted to service to undergraduate students. Annual reports of the library and its sub-units, minutes of staff meetings, and scrapbook dealing mainly with the library's opening during academic year 1957/58; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were transferred from the Undergraduate Library to the Bentley Library in March, 1986 (Donor No. 7308 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Undergraduate Library was conceived of by the university's senior administrators as part of their broader plan to decentralize services then offered by the badly overcrowded university library. The Undergraduate Library, the second such facility built in the nation, was designed to specially serve the needs of the university's undergraduate student population, as well as funnel those students away from the university's original library. Opened for student use on January 16, 1958, the facility contained 50,000 books and a wide array of audiovisual material.
Undergraduate Librarians
1957-1961 Roberta C. Keniston
1962-1981 Rose﷓Grace Faucher
1981 Barbara Kemp (acting)
1981-1985 David A Norden
1985- Barbara MacAdam (acting)
Records of the Undergraduate Library include two linear feet of documents, a few photos and one oversize scrapbook, collectively dating from 1957 to 1982. The documents divide themselves into two categories, annual reports and staff minutes. Reports include those of the Undergraduate Library as a whole (1957/58 to 1981/82) arranged chronologically, and those of the various sub-units within the Library, a`ranged alphabetically by unit name. Staff meeting minutes are complete from 1957 to 1981.
The scrapbook deals largely with the library's opening in academic year 1957/58.
Subjects:
Libraries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan. Undergraduate Library.; Scrapbooks.
- Annual Reports
  - Undergraduate Library
    - 1957/58-1981/82, 25 folders (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Library Departments
    - Acquisitions Office, 1963/64-1981/82 (Box 1)
    - Assistant Head, 1974/75-1980/81 (Box 1)
    - Catalog Office, 1959/60-1980/81 (Box 1)
    - Circulation, 1958-1980/81 (Box 1)
    - Instruction and Orientation, 1975/76-1981/82 (Box 1)
    - Pamphlet Office, 1959/60-1979/80 (Box 1)
    - Periodical office, 1959/60-1980/81 (Box 1)
    - Reference Office, 1958/59-1981/82 (Box 1)
    - Reserve Office, 1957/58-1980/81 (Box 2)
    - Sight and Sound Center, 1958/59-1981/82 (Box 2)
- Staff Meetings
  - Minutes, 1957-1981, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 2)
  - Photographs; "Poetry's Golden Anniversary" Display (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook re Undergraduate Library Opening, 1958/58 (Volume 1)